Register of the Bonner Frank Fellers Papers, 1904-1997
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File I, 1934-1972. (Box 5-15)
  - Taxpayers Committee to End Foreign Aid
    - Correspondence
      - Moffat, Jay P., 1969 (Folder 12: 41)
      - Montana Research Associates, 1968 (Folder 12: 42)
      - Moseley, C. C., 1968 (Folder 12: 43)
      - Nofziger, Lyn, 1968 (Folder 12: 44)
      - Packard, David, 1969 (Folder 12: 45)
      - Palmby, Clarence D., 1969 (Folder 12: 46)
      - Passman, Otto E., 1969-1971 (Folder 12: 47)
      - Petty, John R., 1969 (Folder 12: 48)
      - Peyton, Bernard, 1968 (Folder 12: 49)
      - Republican National Convention, Temporary Committee on Resolutions, 1968 (Folder 12: 50)
      - Rockwell, Willard F., 1968 (Folder 12: 51)
      - The Root of the Matter, 1970 (Folder 12: 52)
      - Rosalind, Countess, 1969 (Folder 12: 53)
      - Ross, Walter G., 1968 (Folder 12: 54)
      - Rostenkowski, Dan, 1968 (Folder 12: 55)
      - Stetson, Charles P., 1968 (Folder 12: 56)
      - Stokes, W. E. D., 1968 (Folder 12: 57)
      - Thoren, Everett, 1969 (Folder 12: 58)
      - Tittman, Edward M., 1971 (Folder 12: 59)
      - University of California, Los Angeles, 1971 (Folder 12: 60)
      - Wade, Leigh, 1968 (Folder 12: 61)
      - Wade, Maury, 1968 (Folder 12: 62)
      - Wallace, D., 1968 (Folder 12: 63)
      - Walsh, Edward A., 1968 (Folder 12: 64)
      - Washington Steel Corporation, Pennsylvania, 1968 (Folder 12: 65)
      - Welch, Mary, 1968 (Folder 12: 66)
      - Wiegand, E. L., 1968 (Folder 12: 67)
      - Wood, Robert E., 1968 (Folder 12: 68)
      - Woodward, M. Truman, 1968 (Folder 12: 69)
      - Ziegler, Ronald L., 1969 (Folder 12: 70)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 12: 71)
    - "Dismal Swamp - Fallacies and Misconceptions in the Report of the President's Task Force on International Development,", undated (Folder 12: 72)
    - Fellers, Bonner, statement before the Senate Committee on Appropriations, 1968 September 24 (Folder 12: 73)
    - Report to the president, 1969 February 20 (Folder 12: 74)
    - Rockwell, Willard F., "A Businessman's View of Our Industrial Progress," speech at Industrial Management Club of New Orleans, Louisiana, 1968 September 16 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - "To the American Taxpayers,", 1971 October 14 (Folder 13: 2)
    - Trust declaration, 1968 (Folder 13: 3)
  - "Thirteenth Broadcast to the Japanese People by Captain Zacharias, United States Navy,", undated (Folder 13: 4)
  - "Typical Japanese Atrocities During the Liberation of the Philippines,", undated (Folder 13: 5)
  - United States. Army. Forces, General Headquarters (GHQ)
    - Information dissemination, 1945 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Operations instructions, 1945
      - August (Folder 13: 7)
      - October-December (Folder 13: 8)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. Central Bureau Liaison Office. General Headquarters. Losses sustained by Japanese army and navy, 1945 September (Folder 13: 9)
  - United States. Army. Forces in the Pacific. General Headquarters. Office of Military Secretary to Commander-in-Chief. Weekly plan for psychological warfare, 1945 April 28 (Folder 13: 10)
  - United States. Army. Forces in the Pacific. General Headquarters, G-3. Historical Division. "Chronology of the War in the Southwest Pacific, 1941-1945,", undated (Folder 13: 11)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. Office of the Assistant Chief of Staff, G-2. Translator and Interpreter Service. "Documents Submitted to the Supreme Commander for the Allied Forces by the Japanese Mission to Negotiate Surrender," Manila, 1945 August 19 (Folder 13: 12)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. Office of the Military Secretary. Psychological Warfare Branch
    - "Basic Military Plan for Psychological Warfare against Japan,", 1945 March/April (Folder 13: 13)
    - Leaflets, 1944-1945 (Folder 13: 14)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. Office of the Military Secretary. Psychological Warfare Branch. Collation Section
    - "Inside Japan - Food Crisis," Special Report No. 3, 1945 June 16 (Folder 13: 15)
    - "Inside Japan - Youth: Pawn of the Militarists," Special Report No. 5, 1945 July 23 (Folder 13: 16)
    - "Japan and Our Ally, Russia," Special Report No. 6, 1945 August 3 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - "Japan's Homefront Morale,", 1945 July 31 (Folder 14: 2)
    - "Japanese Trends of Psychological Significance," Report Nos. 10-12, 1945 May-July (Folder 14: 3)
    - "The Nogi Tradition Past and Present," Special Report No. 1, 1945 May 3 (Folder 14: 4)
    - "Psychological Warfare - Reactions and Developments," Report Nos. 8, 9, 12, 14, 1945 April-July (Folder 14: 5-8)
    - Reviews of significant trends discerned in daily collation summaries, Nos. 1-8, 1944 September - 1945 February (Folder 14: 9)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific. General Headquarters. Scientific and Technical Advisory Section. Report on scientific intelligence survey in Japan, 1945 September-October (Folder 14: 10)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific and Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Operations and signal corps message, 1944-1945 (Folder 14: 11)
  - United States. Army. Forces, Pacific and Southwest Pacific Area. Office of the Military Secretary
    - Field trip reports, 1944 December  1945 April (Folder 14: 12)
    - Routing slip, 1945 (Folder 14: 13)
  - United States. Army, 6th Army
    - Headquarters. Office of the Assistant Chief of Staff, G-2. Interrogation Report No. 0447, 1945 May 7 (Folder 14: 14)
    - Headquarters. Psychological Warfare Branch. Leaflets, charts, and other material, 1944-1945 (Folder 14: 15-16)
  - United States. Army. 6th Army. ATIS Advanced Echelon. Prisoner of War Preliminary Interrogation Report, 1945 March 27 (Folder 14: 17)
  - United States. Army. Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters
    - Communiques, 1945
      - January-June (Folder 14: 18)
      - July-August (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Proclamation providing for military measures to be taken upon apprehension of citizens of the Philippines who voluntarily have given aid, comfort and sustenance to the enemy, 1944 December 29 (Folder 15: 2)
  - United States. Army, Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Allied Translator and Interpreter Section
    - "Antagonism between Officers and Men in the Japanese Armed Forces," Research Report No. 122, 1945 April 19 (Folder 15: 3)
    - "Hoko System in Formosa and As Proposed for the Philippine Islands," Enemy Publications No. 358, 1945 April 28 (Folder 15: 4)
  - United States. Army. Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Office of the Commander-in-Chief. Proclamation to the people of the Philippines, undated (Folder 15: 5)
  - United States. Army. Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Office of the Military Secretary. "Relations between the U.S.S.R. and Japan,", 1945 March (Folder 15: 6)
  - United States. Army. Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Office of the Military Secretary. Psychological Warfare Branch. Leaflets
    - 1944-1945 (Folder 15: 7)
    - 1945 (Folder 15: 8)
  - United States. Army. Southwest Pacific Area. General Headquarters. Office of the Military Secretary. Psychological Warfare Branch. Collation Section
    - "Japanese Trends of Psychological Significance," Report No. 9, 1945 March 25 (Folder 15: 9)
    - "Psychological Warfare  Reaction and Developments," Report No. 11, 1945 June 1 (Folder 15: 10)
  - United States. Army. XI Corps. Headquarters. Psychological Warfare Branch. Leaflet entitled "To Friendly Filipinos,", undated (Folder 15: 11)
  - United States. Army. 33rd Infantry Division. Headquarters. G-2 summaries, 1945
    - March-April (Folder 15: 12)
    - May-June (Folder 15: 13)
    - June (Folder 15: 14)
  - United States foreign aid, 1959-1972 (Folder 15: 15)
  - World War II military situation, 1943 (Folder 15: 16)
  - Miscellany (Folder 15: 17)
- Speeches and Writings I, 1934-1960. (Box 16)
  Speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by title
  - "Answer to Japan,", 1944 July (Folder 16: 1)
  - "Our Mutual Security Program,", undated (Folder 16: 2)
  - "The Philippine Army," Part I, "Commonwealth Defense,", undated (Folder 16: 3)
  - "The Psychology of the Japanese Soldier," Individual Research Study, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas, 1934-1935 (Folder 16: 4)
  - "Report of Travel from Paris to Manila via Vladivostok, May-June 1937,", undated (Folder 16: 5)
  - "Security in the Modern World," Washington, D.C., 1960 (Folder 16: 6)
  - Statement on the Military Assistance Bill, H.R. 5748, before the Committee on Foreign Affairs, House of Representatives, 1949 August 8 (Folder 16: 7)
- Printed Matter, 1945-1972. (Folder 16: 8-41)
  Pamphlets and reprints on a variety of subjects
- Increment of August 1976, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Campaign, Jameson G., "America's Might and Soviet Myth,", 1960 (Folder 16: 42)
- Incremental Materials of 2003, 1904-1997 (Box 17-60)
- Biographical File, 1915-1983. (Box 17)
  Awards, biographies, clippings, interviews, lists, membership card, military records, obituaries, programs, and travel documents, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Awards, certificates, citations, and diplomas, 1915-1972. (Folder 17: 1)
    Includes related correspondence
  - Biographies, 1946-1951. (Folder 17: 2)
    Typescripts
  - Clippings
    - 1943-1957 (Folder 17: 3)
    - 1958-1983 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Interview transcripts.
    - 1967. (Folder 17: 5)
    - 1973. (Folder 17: 6)
  - Lists of publications, undated. (Folder 17: 7)
  - Lists of speaking engagements, undated and 1951. (Folder 17: 8)
  - Membership card, 1941 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Military records, 1936-1946 (Folder 17: 10)
  - Obituaries, 1973. (Folder 17: 11)
    Printed copies
  - Programs, 1956-1959 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Travel documents, 1923-1938 (Folder 17: 13)
- Correspondence II, 1923-1973. (Box 17-27)
  Cards, enclosures, and letters, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    - General
      - Letters concerning speaking engagements, 1949-1952 (Folder 17: 14)
    - A, 1942-1972 (Folder 17: 15)
    - B, 1937-1973 (Folder 17: 16)
    - C, 1942-1971 (Folder 17: 17)
    - D, 1937-1973 (Folder 17: 18)
    - E, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - F, 1942-1967 (Folder 18: 2)
    - G, 1938-1972 (Folder 18: 3)
    - H, 1942-1972 (Folder 18: 4)
    - I, 1950-1954 (Folder 18: 5)
    - J, 1949-1966 (Folder 18: 6)
    - K, 1928-1969 (Folder 18: 7)
    - L, 1944-1968 (Folder 18: 8)
    - M, 1943-1968 (Folder 18: 9)
    - N, 1951-1970 (Folder 18: 10)
    - P, 1940-1965 (Folder 18: 11)
    - R, 1944-1969 (Folder 18: 12)
    - S, 1937-1973 (Folder 18: 13)
    - T, 1942-1972 (Folder 18: 14)
    - W, 1937-1970 (Folder 18: 15)
  - Unidentified, 1940-1967 (Folder 18: 16)
  - Ackerman, Carl W., 1943-1958 (Folder 18: 17)
  - Aircraft Industries Association (B. C. Goss), 1947 (Folder 18: 18)
  - Air University (formerly Air War College), 1948-1954 (Folder 18: 19)
  - Allee, W. Clyde, 1946 (Folder 18: 20)
  - Allen, Gary, 1972 (Folder 18: 21)
  - American Opinion (Scott Stanley, Jr.), 1970 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Andrews, T. Coleman, 1957-1958 (Folder 19: 2)
  - Ayusawa, Iwao, 1950-1955 (Folder 19: 3)
  - Azzam, Abdul Rahman, 1942-1947 (Folder 19: 4)
  - Barbey, D. E., 1951-1966 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Barnes, Harry E., 1950-1960 (Folder 19: 6)
  - Benson, George S., 1972 (Folder 19: 7)
  - Benton, William, 1950 (Folder 19: 8)
  - Bishop, Max W., 1968-1973 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Boldyreff, C. W., 1954-1955 (Folder 19: 10)
  - Brown, Constantine, 1944-1946 (Folder 19: 11)
  - Brown, Katharine Kennedy, 1967-1969 (Folder 19: 12)
  - Brownell, Herbert, Jr., 1948 (Folder 19: 13)
  - Bruce, David, 1943 (Folder 19: 14)
  - Byrd, Richard E., 1945-1946 (Folder 19: 15)
  - Catholic Digest (Paul Bussard), 1954 (Folder 19: 16)
  - Chapman, Conrad, 1968 (Folder 19: 17)
  - Cho, Kiyoko T., 1966 (Folder 19: 18)
  - Clarke, Carter
    - 1936-1945 (Folder 19: 19)
    - 1948-1972 (Folder 19: 20)
  - Clarkson, P. W., 1945 (Folder 19: 21)
  - Cocke, W. H., 1963-1971 (Folder 19: 22)
  - Colegrove, Kenneth, 1949 (Folder 19: 23)
  - Cutler, Charles R., 1957-1966 (Folder 19: 24)
  - DeWitt, Joseph, 1963 (Folder 19: 25)
  - Dondero, George A., 1945 (Folder 19: 26)
  - Donovan, William J., 1944-1945 (Folder 19: 27)
  - Dresser, Robert B., 1966-1973 (Folder 19: 28)
  - Driskell, W. E., 1943 (Folder 19: 29)
  - Druck, Gertrud, 1948-1965 (Folder 19: 30)
  - Dzau, Linson, 1972 (Folder 19: 31)
  - Earlham College (Jay Beede, Landrum R. Bolling, Ruby Davis, W. C. Dennis, J. Douglas Foster, Paul J. Furnas, Robert F. Jackson, Thomas E. Jones, Conrad Joyner, Helen L. Liebert, Florence Long, Hugh Ronald, Roy Shuckman, Robert M. Taylor, Opal Thornberg, Alan M. Walker), 1930-1972 (Folder 19: 32)
  - Edison, Charles, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Elleman, John H., 1963 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Evans, Luther H., 1946 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Fleming, Lamar, 1954 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Fletcher, Paul, 1923-1952 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Flynn, John T., 1957 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Fonveille, John, 1947-1969 (Folder 20: 7)
  - Garrity, Devin A., 1963-1973 (Folder 20: 8)
  - Gill, William J., 1970-1972 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Gipson, J. H., Sr., 1954-1955 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Greene, J. Woodall, 1946-1949 (Folder 20: 11)
  - Groseclose, Elgin, 1971 (Folder 20: 12)
  - Hagiwara, Tom, 1947-1949 (Folder 20: 13)
  - Haley, J. Evetts, 1954-1971 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Hammond, Edith, 1946 (Folder 20: 15)
  - Harnischfeger, Walter, 1968-1973 (Folder 20: 16)
  - Harper, F. A., 1964-1965 (Folder 20: 17)
  - Harrison, Ernest and Anna, 1965-1966 (Folder 20: 18)
  - Harriss, Robert M., 1954-1970 (Folder 20: 19)
  - Haven, Violet Sweet, 1945 (Folder 20: 20)
  - Hawkins, Gertrude Cole, 1957-1970 (Folder 20: 21)
  - Henry Regnery Co. (Henry Regnery, Philip N. Starbuck, William F. Strube, Fred Wieck)
    - 1953 (Folder 20: 22)
    - 1954-1967 (Folder 20: 23)
  - Herbert Hoover Oral History Program (Raymond Henle, Catharine J. Kenny), 1970 (Folder 20: 24)
  - Herbert Hoover Presidential Library Association (John T. McCarty), 1970-1971 (Folder 20: 25)
  - Higgins, Howard, 1952-1953 (Folder 20: 26)
  - Higsen, Karl W., 1945-1946 (Folder 20: 27)
  - Hoerner, R. N., Mrs., 1973 (Folder 20: 28)
  - Honan, William H., 1951 (Folder 20: 29)
  - Hoover, Allan, 1964-1970 (Folder 20: 30)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1939-1964 (Folder 20: 31)
  - Horinouchi, Kensuke, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Hosono, Gunji, 1955-1966 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Howard, Roy M., 1945-1946 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Howe, Frederick C., 1938-1940 (Folder 21: 4)
  - Hunt, Emmie, 1936-1944 (Folder 21: 5)
  - Hunt, Frazier
    - Undated (Folder 21: 6-7)
    - 1926-1945 (Folder 21: 8)
    - 1946-1960 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Jackson, Robert F., 1970 (Folder 21: 10)
  - James, D. Clayton, 1969-1972 (Folder 21: 11)
  - Jenison, Edward H., 1948-1964 (Folder 21: 12)
  - Jenner, William E., 1954-1958 (Folder 21: 13)
  - Johnson, Louis, 1942-1955 (Folder 21: 14)
  - Johnsson, Stephen H., 1955 (Folder 21: 15)
  - Kasai, Jiuji
    - 1945-1964 (Folder 21: 16)
    - 1965-1968 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 22: 2)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Kasai, Michiko, 1968-1969 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Kasé, Toshikazu, 1955 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Kenmayr, Erich, 1957 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Kimmel, Husband E., 1967 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Kimmel, Joseph, 1953-1969 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Kimmel, Joseph S., Jr., 1972 (Folder 22: 9)
  - Kreuter, Bob, 1956 (Folder 22: 10)
  - LaFollete, Philip F., 1944-1961 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Lane, Thomas A., 1965 (Folder 22: 12)
  - Lichatscheff, Boris, 1951 (Folder 22: 13)
  - Lombard, Helen, 1945 (Folder 22: 14)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1939-1951 (Folder 22: 15)
  - MacNeil, Neil, 1957 (Folder 22: 16)
  - MacNider, Hanford, 1945-1949 (Folder 22: 17)
  - Makaroff, V. S., 1951 (Folder 22: 18)
  - Malone, George W., 1955-1959 (Folder 22: 19)
  - Manion, Clarence, 1954-1972 (Folder 22: 20)
  - Manly, Chesly, 1966 (Folder 22: 21)
  - Marshall, A. H., 1942-1945 (Folder 22: 22)
  - Martinez, Maria, 1939-1957 (Folder 22: 23)
  - Mashbir, Sidney Forrester, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Mason, Frank E., 1956-1971 (Folder 23: 2)
  - Mayer, Frederick C., 1944-1973 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Mayer, Robert W., 1970-1972 (Folder 23: 4)
  - McCormick, Chesley, 1968 (Folder 23: 5)
  - Merz, Max, 1949-1958 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Middleton, S. H., 1953 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Moreel, Ben and Cele, 1958-1970 (Folder 23: 8)
  - Morton, A. H., 1943 (Folder 23: 9)
  - Moseley, C. C., 1969-1972 (Folder 23: 10)
  - Mudge, Verne C., 1944 (Folder 23: 11)
  - Murphy, Frank, 1943 (Folder 23: 12)
  - Nelson, Frederic, 1953-1966 (Folder 23: 13)
  - New York Times, 1952 (Folder 23: 14)
  - Nicholson, Ralph, 1943-1946 (Folder 23: 15)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1969-1970 (Folder 23: 16)
  - O'Donnell, John, 1953-1954 (Folder 23: 17)
  - Pabst, Robert E., 1966-1969 (Folder 23: 18)
  - Palmer, Paul, 1943 (Folder 23: 19)
  - Parrish, Noel F., 1951-1963 (Folder 23: 20)
  - Pettengill, Samuel B., 1963-1969 (Folder 23: 21)
  - Pew, J. Howard, 1967-1970 (Folder 23: 22)
  - Piburn, E. W., 1944-1945 (Folder 23: 23)
  - Popovic, Z. R., 1942-1953 (Folder 23: 24)
  - Post, Florence, 1967 (Folder 23: 25)
  - Power, Thomas S., 1959-1960 (Folder 23: 26)
  - Pury, Edward G. de, 1953 (Folder 23: 27)
  - Quirino, Elpidio, undated (Folder 23: 28)
  - Reader's Digest (Francis Drake, Eugene Lyones, James A. McCracken, Paul Palmer, Marc Rose, Robert S. Strother, Dewitt Wallace), 1943-1972 (Folder 23: 29)
  - Reece, Carroll and Louise (Box 24)
    - 1924-1949 (Folder 24: 1)
    - 1950-1953 (Folder 24: 2)
  - Richardson, Brent, 1951 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Rochford, Daniel, 1967 (Folder 24: 4)
  - Rockwell, Willard F., 1964-1968 (Folder 24: 5)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald B., 1958-1963 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Root, E. Merrill, 1966 (Folder 24: 7)
  - Rothermere, Lord, 1936 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Roxas, Manuel, 1947 (Folder 24: 9)
  - Sack, Arkady J., 1949 (Folder 24: 10)
  - Santiago, Luis, 1947 (Folder 24: 11)
  - Sarnoff, David, 1955 (Folder 24: 12)
  - Schaefer, J. Earl
    - 1947-1950 (Folder 24: 13)
    - 1951-1953 (Folder 24: 14)
    - 1954-1955 (Folder 24: 15)
    - 1956-1959 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - 1960-1971 (Folder 25: 2)
  - Schenck, Hubert G., 1947-1948 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis, 1970-1972 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Scott, Hugh, Jr., 1948 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Skinner, Merson L., 1953 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Smith, Dale O., 1954-1969 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Smith, Jessica, 1948 (Folder 25: 8)
  - Smith, Lawrence H., 1949-1950 (Folder 25: 9)
  - Smith, Truman, 1948-1955 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Smithers Hunt, David W., 1942-1943 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Soriano, Andrés
    - 1945-1949 (Folder 25: 12)
    - 1950-1964 (Folder 25: 13)
  - Spaatz, Carl, 1945 (Folder 25: 14)
  - Sprinkle, Ray E., 1951 (Folder 25: 15)
  - Steely, H. M., Jr., 1944-1945 (Folder 25: 16)
  - Stratemeyer, George E., 1944-1967 (Folder 25: 17)
  - Strother, Robert S., 1961-1966 (Folder 25: 18)
  - Sumner, Jessie, 1939-1946 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Taft, Robert A.
    - 1947-1950 (Folder 26: 2)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 26: 3)
  - Taguchi, Shu, 1949 (Folder 26: 4)
  - Tando, José, 1945 (Folder 26: 5)
  - Tarbuck, Ray, 1944-1972 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1946 (Folder 26: 7)
  - Todt, George, 1968-1969 (Folder 26: 8)
  - Trohan, Walter, 1964-1971 (Folder 26: 9)
  - Trudeau, Arthur G., 1965 (Folder 26: 10)
  - Turner, Roscoe, 1966 (Folder 26: 11)
  - Twining, Nathan F., 1952-1966 (Folder 26: 12)
  - Uichango, Conrado B., 1966 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - United States. Army. Chief of Staff (M. B. Ridgway, Maxwell Taylor), 1954-1955 (Folder 27: 2)
  - United States. War Department. Adjutant General's Office (Leon J. Gund, Arthur C. Purvis), 1947 (Folder 27: 3)
  - University of Oregon (Edward Kemp), 1980 (Folder 27: 4)
  - University of Wyoming (Gene M. Gressley), 1981 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Vandenberg, Hoyt S., 1947-1953 (Folder 27: 6)
  - Van Zandt, James E., 1948 (Folder 27: 7)
  - Villa-Real, Luis A., 1950 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Walker, Edwin A., 1959-1965 (Folder 27: 9)
  - Washington, Val, 1947 (Folder 27: 10)
  - Wheat, Clayton E., 1930-1952 (Folder 27: 11)
  - White, Tom, 1945-1973 (Folder 27: 12)
  - Willoughby, Charles, 1949-1950 (Folder 27: 13)
  - Wood, Robert E., 1944-1953 (Folder 27: 14)
  - Woodward, M. Truman, Jr., 1967 (Folder 27: 15)
  - Yale University Press (Eugene Davidson), 1953 (Folder 27: 16)
  - Yasukawa, Takeshi, 1958 (Folder 27: 17)
  - Zilcher, Heinz, 1938 (Folder 27: 18)
- Speeches and Writings II, 1922-1972. (Box 27-37)
  Articles, monographs, and speeches, arranged chronologically
  - "Additional Implications of the Atlantic Alliance,", undated. (Folder 27: 19)
  - "An American Common Sense Peace Plan,", undated. (Folder 27: 20)
  - "America's Warfare State,", undated. (Folder 27: 21)
  - Article on communism, undated. (Folder 27: 22)
  - Article on Douglas MacArthur, undated. (Folder 27: 23)
  - Article on NATO, undated. (Folder 27: 24)
    Typescript fragment
  - Article on Soviet military policy, undated. (Folder 27: 25)
  - Article on the United States Navy, undated. (Folder 27: 26)
  - Article on World War II, undated. (Folder 27: 27)
  - Article urging attack on Japan, undated. (Folder 27: 28)
  - "The Battle of Manila Bay,", undated. (Folder 27: 29)
  - "The Capture of Emilio Aguinaldo by Sergeant Mariano Punla,", undated. (Folder 27: 30)
  - "Comments on the Anti-Aircraft Defense of the U.S.A.,", undated. (Folder 27: 31)
  - "The 'Dreamy Philippines',", undated. (Folder 27: 32)
  - "Emancipation of Japan,", undated. (Folder 27: 33)
  - "The English Course at West Point,", undated. (Folder 27: 34)
  - "The Fight for Peace,", undated. (Folder 27: 35)
  - "Fighting Russia from the Inside: Can the Russian People Revolt?", undated. (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - "Foreign Policy,", undated. (Folder 28: 2)
  - "Friendship, Security and Peace,", undated. (Folder 28: 3)
  - "History of the Philippines,", undated.
    - Typescript (Folder 28: 4)
    - Research materials (Folder 28: 5)
  - "How this War Machine Works,", undated. (Folder 28: 6)
  - "Humorous and Otherwise,", undated. (Folder 28: 7)
  - "Ideas,", undated. (Folder 28: 8)
    Holograph
  - "Impact of Foreign Aid on U.S. Industry,", undated. (Folder 28: 9)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "An Invisible Hand?", undated. (Folder 28: 10)
  - "The Island Fortress of Corregidor,", undated. (Folder 28: 11)
  - "Japanese Background,", undated. (Folder 28: 12)
  - "Japan's Problems Must Be SettledNow!", undated. (Folder 28: 13)
  - "Leadership,", undated. (Folder 28: 14)
  - "Lessons from Korea,", undated. (Folder 28: 15)
  - "Lessons on War,", undated. (Folder 28: 16)
  - "LostOur Power of Decision,", undated. (Folder 28: 17)
  - Memorandum on the situation in the Philippines, undated. (Folder 28: 18)
  - "Military Geography of Japan,", undated. (Folder 28: 19)
  - "Military History in the Far East,", undated. (Folder 28: 20)
  - "National Defense,", undated. (Folder 28: 21)
  - Notes on military policy, undated. (Folder 28: 22)
  - Notes on national defense, undated. (Folder 28: 23)
  - "Notes on Sartor Resartus,", undated. (Folder 28: 24)
  - "Notes on Second World War,", undated. (Folder 28: 25)
  - Notes on Shintoism, undated. (Folder 28: 26)
  - Notes on the American economy, undated. (Folder 28: 27)
  - "Observations on Military Strategy," lecture outline, Alabama, undated. (Folder 28: 28)
  - "On the importance of American History,", undated. (Folder 28: 29)
  - "Our Business Outlook in Japan,", undated. (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - "Our Defense and Our Defenders,", undated. (Folder 29: 2)
  - "Our Impending Gold Crisis," radio broadcast, undated. (Folder 29: 3)
  - "Our Korean Venture,", undated. (Folder 29: 4)
  - "Our Military Assistance Program,", undated. (Folder 29: 5)
  - "Our Mission in the Philippines,", undated. (Folder 29: 6)
  - "Our National Security,", undated. (Folder 29: 7)